

FELIPE CORNEJO

METHODOLOGIST AND PHD IN BIOSCIENCE

15+ years in business innovation, tech/project management, and a strong scientific background in biotech research design. Proven track record in successful startup business model design.

🕋 Avenida José Manuel Balmaceda, 865, Viña del Mar, Chile

**** +56997485098

felipecornejot@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/felipe-cornejo-2bb0a0186/

Education

University of Talca

Upper Second Class. Rank 6/36 2003 - 2007

University of Talca

Msc. Technology Management 2009 - 2014

Nottingham Trent University

Mphil Method of Research 2013 - 2014

Nottingham Trent University

PhD Bioscience

2014 - 2017

Competencies

Making Decisions Analytical Work under pressure Leadership Self-Motivation

References

David Reyes

Founder Agrowalung, SpA +56 9 6541 2900

Tomás Gabriel Bas

Universidad Católica del Norte +56 9 5225 5067

Experience

2013 - Nowadays

Researcher in applied biotech & innovation | Consultant on business innovation | Mentoring and Adviser at Endeavor, **EIVA and CIUC**

- Counseled startups and scaleups, particularly science-based companies, as a research advisor (with Endeavor and EIVA)
- Advisor for research strategies and MVP validation
- Mentoring (project management, research advisor and ecosystem evaluation)

2017-2019

Ekorigen SpA and KL Consultant | Project Manager and R&D

- Biotechnology laboratory coordinator
- Project manager
- Technology manager

2013 - 2019

Part-time lecture of statistics, method of research

- University of Talca
- University of La Frontera
- University San Sebastián

2008 - 2012

University of Talca | Research Assistant, Faculty of Psychology

- Data analysts, writer of statistic reports for research
- Formulation and evaluation of research projects
- Assessment planner

Work skills

- English
- Research methods
- Project management
- **TICs**



Courses

University of Talca

Diploma of Organizational Psychology 2007 - 2008

University of Talca

Diploma of Education based on Competencies 2012 - 2013

Companies Founded

2022-Present

Agrowalüng (Biotech, biocontrols, Agtech)

2020-Present

Palín (Educative Toy Store)

2019-Present

Scout Trading Company (Business innovation, S&T-based companies advisor)

2013-2016

Creativo TMI (Business consultant)

Companies Advised

2022-Present

Trave App (Tourism App)

2020-2022

25 Minutes Kids (Online Education

2019-Present

Industris Ferrero (Business consultant)

2018-Present

Bayer Industries (Agtech Vertical)

2020-Present

Hidroshock (Biotech Company)

2023-Present

Centro de Biotecnología Translacional (SOFOFA)

2023-Present

Centro de Innovación UC (CIUC, Biotech Vertical)

Academic Experience (selected ISI & Scopus publications)

in press. ECharacterisation of the Chilean Biotechnology Industry through Technological and Natural Resource Clusters: Analysis of Regional Entry Barriers. F Cornejo, TG. Bas. Innovation Policy and the Economy

2018. Effectiveness of cognitive-behavioural therapy for post-disaster distress in post-traumatic stress symptoms after Chilean earthquake and tsunami. M Leiva-Bianchi, F Cornejo, A Fresno, C Rojas, C Serrano. Gaceta Sanitaria 32, 291-296

2015. Semantic processing of epistemic and metaphysical words in children and adolescents with Autism Spectrum Disorder (ASD) and Typically Developing (TD). KL Juillerat, FA Cornejo, RD Castillo, SE Chaigneau. TERAPIA PSICOLOGICA 33 (3), 221-238

2013. Empleados y desempleados, atribuciones causales y bienestar subjetivo. E Moyano-Díaz, D Gutiérrez Peña, K Zúñiga Cabrera, FA Cornejo. Psicologia & Sociedade 25 (2), 440-450

2013. Bienestar subjetivo en maximizadores y satisfacedores. E Moyano-Díaz, F Cornejo, M Carreño, A Muñoz. Terapia psicológica 31 (3), 273-280

2011. Creencias y conductas ambientales, liberalismo económico y felicidad. E Moyano-Díaz, **FA Cornejo**, I Gallardo. Acta colombiana de Psicología 14 (2), 69-77

2010. Summation in Predictive Learning in Children. FA Cornejo, RD Castillo, MA Saavedra, EH Vogel. Psicologica: International Journal of Methodology and Experimental Psychology.

2009. Estrategias de codificación de estímulos en el aprendizaje causal humano. A. Díaz, L. Torres, RD. Castillo, **FA Cornejo**, EH Vogel. Psykhe (Santiago).

Projects related to public funding

FUNDING / TOTAL / ROL

FONDECYT / 6 PROJECTS / 3 AS RESEARCH ASSISTANT AND 3 AS CO-RESEARCHER

FONDEF / 3 PROJECTS / 3 AS ASSOCIATED RESEARCH

CNA / 2 PROJECTS / 2 AS ASSOCIATED RESEARCH ON TECHNOLOGY TRANSFER AND INNOVATION STRATEGIES

CORFO / 9 PROJECTS / 2 AS ASSOCIATED RESEARCH, ASSOCIATED AND OR PROFESIONAL ADVISOR ON TECHNOLOGY TRANSFER AND MVP VALIDATION

Directories and Research positions

PRESIDENT OF INDICATOR COMMITTEE (INNOVATION AND BUSINESS), EIVA, CHILE

ASSOCIATED RESEARCHER ADVISOR ENDEAVOR CHILE AND GLOBAL

ASSOCIATED RESEARCHER COLLABORATOR GEIAL (INNOVATION ECOSYSTEMS)